X-Rated 2: The Greatest Adult Stars of All-Time is a
documentary film directed by Eli Cross.
Documentary sequel that offers a close-up look into the personal lives of the legendary
porn stars who've survived the test of time and influenced popular culture.
Blends rare interviews with erotic clips and additional appearances by Whoopi Goldberg,
Steven Soderbergh and a host of adult stars, directors and trendsetters.
Host - Himself, played by Mr. Skin.
Host - Herself, played by Alana Cruise.
Host - Herself, played by Nadia Jay.
Host - Herself, played by Leigh Raven.
Host - Himself, played by Chad White.
Self, played by Ron Jeremy.
A pornographic film actor or actress, pornographic performer, adult entertainer, or porn star is a
person who performs sex acts on video that is usually characterized as a pornographic film.
Such videos tend to be made in a number of distinct pornographic
subgenres and attempt to present a sexual fantasy.
The actors selected for a particular role are primarily selected
on their ability to create or fit that fantasy.
Pornographic videos are characterized as either softcore, which does not contain depictions of sexual penetration or
extreme fetishism, and hardcore, which can contain depictions of penetration or extreme fetishism, or both.
The genres and sexual intensity of videos is mainly determined by demand.
Depending on the genre of the film, the on-screen appearance, age, and physical features of the actors
and their ability to create the sexual mood of the video is of critical importance.
Most actors specialize in certain genres, such as straight, bisexual, gay, lesbian, bondage, strap-on, anal, double
penetration, semen swallowing, orgy, gang bang, age roleplay, fauxcest, interracial, teenage (18-19) or MILFs and more.
The pornography industry in the United States was the first to develop its
own movie star system, primarily for commercial reasons.
In other countries, the "star" system is not
common, with most actors being amateurs.
Most performers use a pseudonym and strive to maintain off-screen anonymity.
A number of pornographic film actors and actresses have written autobiographies.
It is very rare for pornographic film actors and actresses to
successfully cross over to the mainstream film industry.
Certain pornographic film actors have leveraged their success to branch into
different entrepreneurial endeavours, such as Jenna Jameson's ClubJenna.
Leaked patient database of Adult Industry Medical Health Care Foundation in 2011 contained details of over 12,000 pornographic film actors that
it had tested since 1998, providing estimates of the number of pornographic film actors who have worked in the United States.
As of 2011, it was reported that roughly 1,200–1,500
performers were working in California's "Porn Valley"